William Marquardt

Curitiba, Paraná, Brazil



williammqt@gmail.com



+5541984282865



linkedin.com/in/williammqt

Summary

I'm a Software Engineer and Architect with 10 years of experience. I started my career working as a full-stack engineer, and after six years I decided to work as a backend engineer. I have strong knowledge about the software development process, especially in Backend, Infra, Cloud, Cybersecurity, Databases, and DevOps.

I'm a problem solver and really like to work on solving issues and creating better solutions. I'm passionate about open-source (FOSS), Cybersec, Software quality and performance.

Main skills:

Languages: Python, Bash, Javascript, Golang, Rust;

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, Redis, Cassandra, Aerospike, PostgreSQL;

Cloud: GCP, Heroku, AWS, IBM Cloud;

OS: Linux, BSD

Experience



Software engineer

Globo

Jan 2021 - Present (1 year 2 months +)

At the beginning of 2021, I started to work at Globo, the biggest media-tech company in Latin America. I've Always been fascinating with Globo innovations and I always followed events and talks with Globo engineers. I am part of the DB-Dev Team, which creates solutions for Database admins. Our main product is the DBaaS, an open-source platform like Amazon RDS which provisions and manages databases on demand, currently compatible with Redis, MongoDB and MySQL databases.

Main Activities:

Contribution in defining new technologies and architecture for new services;

Implementing new features in Diango application;

Creating and maintaining some Flask APIs which works as integrated system;

Implementing GCP integration;

Migrating all databases infrastructure to GCP;

Implementing new pipelines and integration tests using Cypress;

Implementing Flask CI to APIs and migrate current test from Travis to Github CI;

Implementing integrations across DBaaS and other platforms using REST APIs;

Main Technologies: Python, Bash, Go, Django, Celery, Flask, GCP, Redis, Mysql, MongoDB, PubSub, Jenkins, Cypress, Docker, Tsuru



Trade na Mão

Apr 2020 - Jan 2021 (10 months)

In 2020 I started working as a tech lead at Trade na Mão. It was a totally new experience, because, in addition to the technical assignments, this was my first contact with leadership, which was my biggest challenge in this period.

Main activities:

Definition of new services architecture and technologies;

Python / NodeJS application development;

Implementing continuous integration using CircleCI;

VPN implementation:

Implementation of server monitoring using MUNIN;

Implementation of automatic deployment;

Implementation of security policies;

Participation in the hiring process / technical interview;

SCRUM master;

Technical reference for the team;

Main Technologies: Python, Go, Docker, NodeJS, Redis, MySQL, SocketIO, Electron, Nginx, Cloudflare.



Software Engineer

Navegg

Jun 2018 - Mar 2020 (1 year 10 months)

After working for about a year and a half as a full-stack, I was promoted and started working exclusively with the back-end. This gave me the opportunity to work in areas that I have affinities with, such as infrastructure and security. I learned a lot about performance, scale, and quality. My biggest challenge in this period was to maintain a system with billions of daily requests in addition to implementing new technologies from POCs.

Main activities:

Administration of Linux and FreeBSD systems;

Development of Python, Javascript and Bash applications;

Development of automated tests;

Database Administration Mysql, Cassandra, Aerospike and Redis;

Development and maintenance of highly scalable services;

VPN / DNS / Firewall configuration and maintenance;

Development of tools for intrusion testing;

Analysis and planning of new products;

MySQL tuning:

Development of unit test using Jasmine and Karma;

Development of integration test using Protractor;

Main Technologies: Python, Bash, Go, Cloudflare, MySQL, Cassandra, Aerospike, Redis, FreeBSD, Docker, Nginx, RabbitMQ, Karma, Jasmine, Protractor.

Full-stack Developer

Navegg

Dec 2016 - Jun 2018 (1 year 7 months)

I joined Navegg at the end of 2016 when I moved to Curitiba. My main challenge in this initial period was to rewrite the Data Management Platform. The backend and frontend were rewritten using Django 2.0 and AngularJS. Also, I was responsible for maintaining the application from analyzing requirements for new features to deploy the application.

Main activities:

SPA development and maintenance (Django + AngularJs);

Development of Js, Python, and Bash Scripts;

ETL for data migration;

Maintenance of Linux Servers;

Main Technologies: Git, Python, Javascript, MySQL, Django, AngularJS, Bash, Nginx

ш

Full-stack Developer / Co-founder

Canvas Studio

Sep 2013 - Oct 2016 (3 years 2 months)

Canvas Studio was a company focused on digital solutions where I was a co-founder. We had the main idea at the end of 2013 and in May 2014 we passed the selection process for the business incubator - Mafratec, which was based at the University of Contestado.

Main activities:

Creation of institutional websites;

Analysis and development of web software;

Administration of Linux servers;

Main Technologies: PHP, Javascript, MySQL, Apache, Linux, Codeigniter, Laravel, Doctrine, AngularJS.



Software Developer

Support Informática

Mar 2011 - May 2014 (3 years 3 months)

Since the beginning of my career I was very interested in software development, so the moment a vacancy appeared in the development area, I asked to take the place left by the former developer. I had little knowledge of programming and this was the opportunity I wanted to start putting this into practice and learn more.

Main activities:

Development and maintenance of software for NF-e, CT-e, PAF / ECF, among others in the Visual Basic 6 language;

Development of institutional websites;

Development of web systems;

Configuration of WTS servers;

Main Technologies: Visual Basic, PHP, MySQL, Javascript, Windows Server.



Information Technology Support Analyst

Support Informática

Mar 2010 - Feb 2011 (1 year)

I joined Support Informática to work with maintenance and technical support of the company's systems. It was a really cool experience because I was able to put into practice what I learned on the internship and improving other points such as customer service and priority control.

Main activities:

Computer maintenance;

Technical support;

Remote access:

Support ticket control;



Information Technology Intern

SENAI/SC - Serviço Nacional de Aprendizagem Industrial

Apr 2009 - Mar 2010 (1 year)

My first job experience during the first year of the technical course in computer networks.

Main activities:

Computer maintenance;

Network maintenance;

Supervision of computer labs;

Education



🥵 Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Paraná

Specialization, CyberSecurity

2021 - 2022

UNOPAR - Universidade Norte do Paraná

Associate's degree, System Analysis and Developmen 2014 - 2017



SENAI/SC - Serviço Nacional de Aprendizagem Industrial

Technical certificate, Computer networks 2009 - 2010

Licenses & Certifications







Skills

Linux • Python • Django • Administração de sistemas Linux • Segurança da informação • Desenvolvimento de software • Firewalls • System Administration • Bash • Git